Luong Van Tu

luongvantuit@gmail.com

+84965445305

GitHub

SUMMARY

I'm Software Engineer. I have 1 year experience in Backend & Ops. I'm a person who is passionate about learning new things, especially in the field of technology. I'm a person who is always willing to learn and share knowledge with others.

SKILLS

• Languages: Python, Golang, Javascript.

• DBSM: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Technologies: CI/CD, K8sPattern: DDD, Saga, Outbox

EDUCATION

University of Science, Vietnam National University Hanoi - Ha Noi, Vietnam

October 2019 - Present

Experience

Open Techiz

Mektoube & Mashallah

March 2023 - Present

- Role: Backend Developer
- **Description:** Mektoube & Mashallah aims to develop a mobile dating application specifically designed for Muslim individuals, creating a platform for communication and connection among users who share common religious values and beliefs. The application will provide features to assist users in finding and connecting based on preferences, religious beliefs, and marriage goals.
- DBMS: MySQL, MongoDB
- Technologies: Golang, Javascript, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Redis, RabbitMQ, Prosody XMPP,...
- Responsibilities:
 - Maintain BackOffice system of Mektoube & Mashallah applications.
 - Added new features for Mektoube & Mashallah applications.
 - Tracking Google, Apple, and Stripe transactions when using buy a subscription or the in-app purchase.

AusVie

Logistics system

February 2022 - March 2023

- Role: Fullstack Developer
- **Description:** AusVie is a project that aims to develop a simple mobile and web application that allows users to conveniently and easily book freight shipments from Australia to Vietnam. The application will provide features for order management, shipment tracking.
- **DBMS:** PostgreSQL.
- Technologies: Terraform, NextJS, Strapi, AWS (ECS, ECR, RDS),...
- Responsibilities:
 - As a DevOps person, my task is to install a CI/CD system with the tool Bitbucket pipelines to test and deploy software on AWS and build Terraform modules to deploy Infrastructure to AWS.
 - After the infrastructure issues have stabilized, as a Backend Developer, I participate in building the basic features of the system, designing the database, and providing services around the functions and requirements of the system
 - As a Front End Developer, I support completing the customer-side user interface and interacting with user APIs.
 - Finally, I completed the functionality of the application for AusVie employees, to update the status of shipping orders and track them.

ACTIVITIES

Build On Vietnam 2021

August 2021 - Sep 2021

- **Description:** Join with Techcombank FACT team to recommend & demo a solution for Techcombank. This application help customer can manage their account, money more easily.
- Finalist Build On Contest Certificates

HAMIC - HUS Applied Mathematics and Informatics Club

June 2021 - Present

- Head of Design & Development Web
- The organizers of the club's activities, such as: WContest: Web for Education.